<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-06-16T21:03:31+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Boutroslab GitHub</title><subtitle>This is the Boutroslab GitHub repository hosting our open source software and supplemental data files</subtitle><author><name>Boutros Lab</name></author><entry><title type="html">CRISPR Library Designer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/CRISPR-Library-Designer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CRISPR Library Designer" /><published>2019-06-10T21:34:30+02:00</published><updated>2019-06-10T21:34:30+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/CRISPR-Library-Designer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/CRISPR-Library-Designer/">&lt;p&gt;The CRISPR library designer (CLD) is an integrated software application for the design of  single guide RNA (sgRNA) libraries for all organisms with annotated genomes. CLD is suitable for the design of libraries using modified CRISPR enzymes and targeting non-coding regions. The software is an end-to-end workflow for the fully automated design of small and large-scale CRISPR libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CLD predicts a high fraction of functional sgRNAs and is publicly available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/boutroslab/cld&quot;&gt;https://github.com/boutroslab/cld&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reference:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heigwer F, Zhan T, Breinig M, Winter J, Brügemann, D, Leible D, Boutros M (2019) CRISPR library designer (CLD): software for multispecies design of single guide RNA libraries, Genome Biology
&lt;a href=&quot;https://genomebiology.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13059-016-0915-2&quot;&gt;doi:10.1186/s13059-016-0915-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Boutros Lab</name></author><category term="Software" /><category term="CRISPR" /><summary type="html">The CRISPR library designer (CLD) is an integrated software application for the design of single guide RNA (sgRNA) libraries for all organisms with annotated genomes. CLD is suitable for the design of libraries using modified CRISPR enzymes and targeting non-coding regions. The software is an end-to-end workflow for the fully automated design of small and large-scale CRISPR libraries.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">HTSvis - a web app for exploratory data analysis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/HTS-visualizer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HTSvis - a web app for exploratory data analysis " /><published>2019-06-09T16:34:30+02:00</published><updated>2019-06-09T16:34:30+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/HTS-visualizer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/HTS-visualizer/">&lt;p&gt;HTSvis is an R/Shiny open-source web application for interactive visualization and exploratory analysis of data from arrayed high-throughput screens. The web application is either available via http://htsvis.dkfz.de/ or can be installed as an R package as described here. Shiny allows that the usage of the application in the default web browser does not require any bioinformatics training. Input data can either be a result file obtained upon analysis with the Bioconductor/R package cellHTS or a generic table with raw or analyzed data from, e.g. a high-content microscopy screen. Data has to be aggregated per well to be imported in HTSvis. Tools to aggregate single cell data from microscopy screens are available in CellProfiler Analyst, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reference&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scheeder C, Heigwer F, Boutros M. (2017). HTSvis: a web app for exploratory data analysis and visualization of arrayed high-throughput screens. &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1093/bioinformatics/btx319&quot;&gt;Bioinformatics 33:2960-2962.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Boutros Lab</name></author><category term="Software" /><category term="HTS" /><category term="Web app" /><summary type="html">HTSvis is an R/Shiny open-source web application for interactive visualization and exploratory analysis of data from arrayed high-throughput screens. The web application is either available via http://htsvis.dkfz.de/ or can be installed as an R package as described here. Shiny allows that the usage of the application in the default web browser does not require any bioinformatics training. Input data can either be a result file obtained upon analysis with the Bioconductor/R package cellHTS or a generic table with raw or analyzed data from, e.g. a high-content microscopy screen. Data has to be aggregated per well to be imported in HTSvis. Tools to aggregate single cell data from microscopy screens are available in CellProfiler Analyst, for example.</summary></entry></feed>