<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://boutroslab.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://boutroslab.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-06-16T11:05:35+02:00</updated><id>https://boutroslab.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Boutroslab Github</title><subtitle>This is the Boutroslab Github repository hosting our open source software and supplemental data files</subtitle><author><name>Boutros Lab</name></author><entry><title type="html">CRISPR Library Designer</title><link href="https://boutroslab.github.io/CRISPR-Library-Designer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CRISPR Library Designer" /><published>2019-06-10T21:34:30+02:00</published><updated>2019-06-10T21:34:30+02:00</updated><id>https://boutroslab.github.io/CRISPR-Library-Designer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://boutroslab.github.io/CRISPR-Library-Designer/">&lt;p&gt;The CRISPR library designer (CLD) is an integrated software application for the design of  single guide RNA (sgRNA) libraries for all organisms with annotated genomes. CLD is suitable for the design of libraries using modified CRISPR enzymes and targeting non-coding regions. The software is an end-to-end workflow for the fully automated design of small and large-scale CRISPR libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CLD predicts a high fraction of functional sgRNAs and is publicly available at https://github.com/boutroslab/cld&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reference:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heigwer F, Zhan T, Breinig M, Winter J, Brügemann, D, Leible D, Boutros M (2019) CRISPR library designer (CLD): software for multispecies design of single guide RNA libraries, Genome Biology
&lt;a href=&quot;https://genomebiology.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13059-016-0915-2&quot;&gt;doi:10.1186/s13059-016-0915-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Boutros Lab</name></author><category term="Software" /><category term="CRISPR" /><summary type="html">The CRISPR library designer (CLD) is an integrated software application for the design of single guide RNA (sgRNA) libraries for all organisms with annotated genomes. CLD is suitable for the design of libraries using modified CRISPR enzymes and targeting non-coding regions. The software is an end-to-end workflow for the fully automated design of small and large-scale CRISPR libraries.</summary></entry></feed>